cmcmarkets.com 2019-04-13

# Privacy & Security Policy| CMC Markets

CMC Markets is committed to protecting the privacy of all personal information that we obtain from you. Our privacy and security policy explains how and why we collect personal information about you, and how that information is maintained and used ("Privacy and Security Policy"). This Privacy and Security Policy applies to all organisations within the CMC Markets group of companies ('CMC Markets'), including CMC Markets UK plc, and covers the following:

CMC Markets may change this privacy policy from time to time. When such a change is made, we will post a revised version online. Changes will be effective from the point at which they are posted. It is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically so you’re aware of any changes. By using our services you agree to this privacy policy. This privacy policy was last changed in May 2018. 

## What information are we collecting and how are we collecting it?

We will collect and process the following personal information about you:

  *  **Information you provide to us**  
You provide us with personal information by filling in the application or other forms on our website or the CMC platform, by accessing and trading on your account through our platform or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. The information you provide us may include your name, address, contact details, financial information about your income and wealth, professional and employment details, trading history and other personal information.
  *  **Information we collect about you**  
We will also collect information about you through your use of this website and our platform.  This information may include site areas visited, pages viewed, frequency and duration of visits. 
  *  **Information we receive from other sources**  
We may also collect your personal information from third parties, including, for example, business partners, analytics providers, search information providers, credit reference agencies and third party marketing companies or through publicly available sources. 
  *  **Monitoring of communications**  
Subject to applicable laws, we will monitor and record your calls, emails, text messages, social media messages and other communications in relation to your dealings with us. We will do this for regulatory compliance, crime prevention and detection, to protect the security of our communications systems and procedures, for quality control and staff training, and when you need to see a record of what’s been said. We will also monitor activities on your account where necessary for these reasons and this is justified by our legitimate interests or our legal obligations.

## Why we collect your information

CMC Markets collects your personal information in order to provide you with our products and services and to establish and manage your account. By collecting your information, CMC Markets is able to monitor and improve the services we offer to our existing and potential clients. 

## How we use your information

CMC Markets may use information for any one or more of the following purposes:

  * to provide the services to you that you have requested including processing transactions;
  * to verify your identity;
  * to maintain your personal profile and manage your account;
  * to contact you when necessary or appropriate in relation to the services being provided to you;
  * to keep you updated whilst you are a client in relation to matters such as your trading activities and activities of CMC Markets;
  * to manage and administer the products and services provided to you;
  * to provide you with information regarding the products and services offered by CMC Markets;
  * to develop an understanding of the products and services that you may be interested in obtaining from CMC Markets;
  * to provide you with information or opportunities that we believe may be relevant to you;
  * to tailor the website or other service we provide to you to your needs and interests; and
  * to create anonymised statistical data. We may share anonymised data with other companies, however this data will not include any information that personally identifies you.

When we collect and use your personal information, we will make sure this is only done in accordance with at least one of the legal grounds available to us under Data Protection law.

 **Using your personal data: the legal basis and purposes**

We will process your personal data: 

As necessary to perform your contract with us for the relevant account(s), or services:

  * To take steps at your request prior to entering into it;
  * To decide whether to enter into it;
  * To manage and perform that contract;
  * To update your records; and
  * To trace your whereabouts or contact you about your account and recovering debt.

As necessary for your own legitimate interests or those of other persons and organisations, eg:

  * For good governance, accounting, and managing and auditing your business operations;
  * To carry out at credit reference agency searches;
  * To monitor emails, calls, other communications, and activities on your account;
  * For market research, analysis and developing statistics; and
  * To carry out marketing and send communications, including tailored messaging by email, post, text, or agreed forms of communication including social media campaigns.

As necessary to comply with a legal obligation, eg:

  * When you exercise your rights under data protection law and make requests;
  * For compliance with legal and regulatory requirements and related disclosures;
  * For activities relating to the prevention, detection and investigation of crime;
  * To verify your identity,  fraud prevention and anti-money laundering checks; and
  * To monitor emails, calls, other communications, and activities on your account.

Based on your consent, eg:

  * When you request us to disclose your personal data to other people or organisations such as a company handling a claim on your behalf, or otherwise agree to disclosures; and
  * To carry out marketing in instances when we have asked for your consent.

You are free at any time to change your mind and withdraw your consent.

## Who may we disclose your information to

CMC Markets may provide your personal information to: 

  * the Financial Conduct Authority and other regulatory and government bodies from time to time in the UK and other countries;
  * any court or tribunal;
  * financial institutions and other similar organisations that we deal with in the course of our corporate activities or those that are nominated by you;
  * if you were introduced to CMC Markets by an introducing broker, introducing brokers;
  * external service providers and professional advisers (which may be located overseas) that provide services to CMC Markets, including credit reference agencies;
  * any organisation at your request or any persons acting on your behalf, including your financial adviser, broker, solicitor or accountant;
  * any third party service providers where this is necessary to process a transaction or provide services which you have requested; or
  * any authority to whom CMC Markets is required to disclose such information by law.

Please note that CMC Markets does not sell or provide your personal information to third parties for marketing purposes.

CMC Markets also requires that external organisations, outside of CMC Markets, who handle or obtain personal information acknowledge the confidentiality of this information and undertake to respect any individual’s right to privacy and comply with all of the relevant data protection laws and this Privacy and Security Policy.

## The personal information we hold about you

Your rights are as follows in respect of the personal information we hold about you:

  * The right to be informed about processing of your personal data;
  * The right to have your personal data corrected if it’s inaccurate and to have incomplete personal data completed;
  * The right to object to processing of your personal data;
  * The right to restrict processing of your personal data;
  * The right to have your personal data erased (the "right to be forgotten");
  * The right to request access to a copy of your personal data and information about how we process it. Please make all requests for access in writing (see how to contact us for details) and provide us with evidence of your identity;
  * The right to move, copy or transfer your personal data (“data portability”); and
  * Rights in relation to automated decision making including profiling.

Please note, some of these rights only apply in certain circumstances and we may not be able to fulfil every request.

You can contact us by sending an email to [helpdeskteamuk@cmcmarkets.com](mailto:helpdeskteamuk@cmcmarkets.com). If you prefer to contact us via phone or by postal service, please refer to the below section "How to contact us".

​We will stop processing your personal data unless the processing is for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims or we have a legitimate business purpose or legal grounds for the processing.

## How we protect your information

CMC Markets is committed to protecting the privacy of all personal information, which CMC Markets obtains from you.

We continue to adopt industry and information security best practices to protect your personal information and ensure unauthorised persons do not access it. Measures include encryption of data during transmission, strong authentication mechanisms, cyber security processes and secure access to machines and data.​

We train our employees who handle personal information to respect the confidentiality of customer data and the privacy of individuals. 

We may transfer personal information to other countries outside of the European Economic Area, such as the USA. In such circumstances we will ensure the transfer is lawful and that there are appropriate security arrangements.

## How long we hold your information

We will remove any personal information that will identify you or we will securely destroy the records when we consider that that personal information is no longer required. This could be a period of seven years after our business relationship with you has ended. 

However, we may need to maintain certain records for a longer period, for example, where we are required to hold your personal information for regulatory or legal purposes, to provide you with the services you have requested or to maintain adequate business records.​

## Cookies and other website

CMC Markets uses cookies to gather information about your access to this website and other services we provide to you. Cookies are small pieces of information, which use a unique identification tag and are stored on your device because of you using this website or other service we provide to you.

They enhance your browsing experience in various ways, which include remembering your preference settings, displaying relevant content and ensuring web pages function as intended. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see our cookie policy.

You can control cookies by changing the settings in the web browser on your computer or tablet and mobile, to manage the functionality of cookies on your mobile phone, please refer to your handset manufacturer or mobile browser guide. 

Some services may not function or have more limited functionality if your web browser does not accept cookies.  To read a guide about cookies from the Interactive Advertising Bureau, visit: [allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/). This site includes instructions on how to amend your cookie settings for a variety of browsers and how to delete existing cookies from your computer.   

When you use this website or other services, we provide to you, you may be able to link to other websites. This Privacy and Security Policy does not apply to those sites. CMC Markets encourages you to read the privacy policies on such sites.​

CMC Markets may change this privacy policy from time to time. When such a change is made, we will post a revised version online. Changes will be effective from the point at which they are posted. It is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically so you’re aware of any changes. By using our services you agree to this privacy policy. This privacy policy was last changed in May 2018. 

## What to do if you have a complaint

If you have any questions or complaints about the way CMC Markets handles your information please contact us. If CMC Markets does not resolve a complaint to your satisfaction, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office ("ICO"). You can find details about how to do this on the ICO website at [ico.org.uk/concerns](https://www.ico.org.uk/concerns) or by calling their helpline 0303 123 1113.  

## Changes to our Privacy and Security Policy

CMC Markets may change this privacy policy from time to time. When such a change is made, we will post a revised version online. Changes will be effective from the point at which they are posted. It is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically so you’re aware of any changes. By using our services you agree to this privacy policy. This privacy policy was last changed in May 2018.

If you have any questions about this Privacy and Security Policy or want to exercise your rights, please contact us by:

​​​• Phone on +44 (0)20 7170 8200;   
​• Email at [helpdeskteamuk@cmcmarkets.com](mailto:helpdeskteamuk@cmcmarkets.com); or email at [dpo@cmcmarkets.com](mailto:dpo@cmcmarkets.com)  
• Post to CMC Markets, Customer Services, 133 Houndsditch, London, EC3A 7BX.
